The spines in the stone mask are capable of piercing a human brain.
But they lack the power to pierce our immortal brains.
We need more power.
Oh, what's this?
This is a Red Stone of Aja, a rare and beautiful gem.
They refract light billions of times over,
making them incredibly strong and pure.
Their power is miraculous.
But still not enough!
These tiny stones don't give the spines enough strength.
(ｶｰｽﾞ)この石仮面の骨針は➡
To complete the stone mask, we need a flawless Red Stone.
人間の脳を
押すことはできる！➡
しかし 不死身の肉体を持つ➡
We need a Super Aja.
我々の脳を 押すには
パワーが足りない！
Once we have it...
もっと パワーが必要だ｡
...we will conquer the sun, and become
the final, perfect progression in evolution.
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)おおっ これは…｡
この赤石は エイジャといって➡
The stone masks were invented by
the most intelligent among them, Cars.
自然界にも めったにない
美しい宝石｡
結晶内で 光は
何億回も 反射を繰り返し➡
Cars crossed the Atlantic in search of
the Super Aja with Wham and AC/DC.
増幅し 浄化されて
一点より 放射される｡
Suzi Q.
Yes, Madam Lisa Lisa, here it is.
自然が作り出した
奇跡のパワーよ｡➡
Thank you.
だが… 不足だ！
In my hand is a perfectly flawless, natural crystal.
この小さな
赤石のパワーでは➡
まだ 骨針の押しは
弱いのだ｡➡
A Super Aja!
石仮面を 完成させるには
完全なる 一点の曇りもない赤石➡
You had the Red Stone of Aja this entire time?!
スーパーエイジャを
はめ込まねばならん！➡
それを かぶったとき➡
我々は 太陽を克服し
進化の最終段階➡
The Pillar Men defeated the warriors of The Ripple to try and get it...
完全なる生き物となるのだ！
...but the Super Aja evaded them. It is now my duty to protect it.
(ﾘｻﾘｻ)石仮面を
発明したのは➡
一番高い知能を
持つといわれる カーズ！
Caesar, I know how you must feel...
(ｼﾞｮｾﾌ･ｼｰｻﾞｰ)えっ!?
カーズは
スーパーエイジャを求め➡
The stone masks killed our grandparents, along with countless others.
ワムウとエシディシを連れて
大西洋を渡ったのです｡
スージーＱ｡
(ｽｰｼﾞｰＱ)はい リサリサ様｡
And we've met its inventor, Cars.
お持ちしました｡
ありがとう｡
Smash it!
そして
これが 一点の曇りもない➡
Let's smash the Red Stone to pieces!
自然が生んだ 奇跡の完全結晶！
If you break it, they'll cry like babies!
スーパーエイジャ！
I can't do that.
(ｼﾞｮｾﾌ･ｼｰｻﾞｰ)おお～！
Why not?!
Legend has it that they cannot be killed without the stone.
(ｼﾞｮｾﾌ)エイジャの赤石を
あんたが 持っていたのか!?
Why the hell not?
(ｼﾞｮｾﾌ･ｼｰｻﾞｰ)うお～！
I have no idea.
Regardless, I will perform my duty as guardian.
波紋の戦士は
柱の男たちに➡
滅ぼされはしましたが➡
辛くも
このスーパーエイジャは 守られ➡
Jojo, Caesar...
私が 守りの使命を
続けているのです｡
You must take your final exam.
(ｼｰｻﾞｰ)くっ…｡
A-A final exam?!
《シーザー
お前の思い 分かるぜ！➡
Caesar, you must defeat Messina.
かつて
俺の祖父も お前の祖父も➡
Jojo, you must defeat Loggins!
多くの人間を
悲劇に追い込んだ 石仮面｡➡
それを 作ったやつが
カーズだったとは…》
ぶっ壊せ！
えっ？
その赤石を ぶっ壊せよ！
Shijima no soko kara
From out of the stillness
破壊しちゃえばよ
やつら 泣いて悔しがるぜ！
それは できません｡
何～!?
Timing:
Fadeout4
エイジャの赤石を 破壊したら➡
Timing:
Fadeout4
Mezameru sono hashira tachi
The Pillars of the past are awakening
彼らを 倒せなくなるとの
言い伝えがあるのです｡
Editor:
Tonitonichopchop
Toki wo koe
To the dawn of a new day
Editor:
何だ？ それは｡
Tonitonichopchop
Editor:
分かりません｡
Shinku no chishio ga
The river of crimson blood within you
しかし 私は 自分の使命を➡
Fadeout4
Typesetting:
守り通さねばならない｡
Fadeout4
Mazrim
Quality Check:
Tachiagaru yuuki wo hikiawaseru
Carries with it the courage to stand and fight
ジョジョ シーザー➡
あなたたち２人に
最終試練を行います｡
(ｼﾞｮｾﾌ･ｼｰｻﾞｰ)さ… 最終試練!?
Uketsugu ai wo sadame to yobu nara
Even if the love I feel is just part of my legacy...
シーザー
あなたは メッシーナと➡
ジョジョ
あなたは ロギンズと戦い➡
勝利するのです！
ぐっ…｡
Hohoemu me de tsugi no te wo
I'll still be smiling as I stay one step ahead
Yami wo azamuite setsuna wo kawashite
Defying the darkness and dodging death at every turn
Encoding:
Fadeout4
Yaiba surinuke yatsura no suki wo tsuke
Slipping past the knife's edge and striking when you least expect
Tsuranuita omoi ga mirai wo hiraku
The emotions running through me blaze a path to the future...
Raw Hunter: WRRRRY
Like a bloody storm
Atsuku like a bloody storm
Burning like a bloody storm
Ketsumyaku ni kizamareta innen ni
When the time comes to end the vendetta carried by our blood
Distro:
ExWizzard
Ukiagaru kienai hokori no kizuna
Remember that the bonds of pride will carry you through any storm
Nigirishimete
So hold them close
http://www.some-stuffs.com
Episode 17: "The Deeper Plan"
You ready, Caesar?
(ﾒｯｼｰﾅ)よいな シーザー｡
望むところだ！
I'm more than ready!
うおおお！
(ﾒｯｼｰﾅ)はあああああ！
It's almost dawn....
《もうすぐ 夜明けだが
夜明け前が 一番暗い…➡
It's always darkest before dawn....
Now where on earth is Loggins hiding?
ロギンズ師範代め！
どこに いやがるんだ…➡
しかし 油断はしねえぜ！
しごきの恨みだ｡➡
I gotta stay sharp.
He and I have a score to settle!
ぶちのめしてくれるぜ！》
むっ!?
Is that instructor Loggins?
ロギンズ師範代か!?
うう… い… 異様だ！
ふ… 不自然だ！
H-How awful!
I-It's unnatural!
Instructor Loggins!
ロギンズ師範代！
H-He's dead!
し… 死んでいる！
A-AC/DC!
エ… エシディシ！
So you came to Venice, to this island.
てめえが このヴェネチアへ➡
この島へ 来たということは…｡
ふぅ…｡
うっ…｡
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)フッ…➡
ん？
隣の島だったか…➡
To think that the woman guarding the Stone is just an island over.
エイジャの赤石を持つ女が
いるという島は｡
His lungs were wrenched out...
肺が えぐられ なくなっている｡
Lungs are paramount for Ripple-users.
肺は 波紋使いにとって 急所｡
あっという間の
一撃の蹴りだったに違いない｡
It must have been one swift kick.
この 威張り散らしのロギンズ…｡
The tyrannical Loggins... you yelled at me for three weeks.
がなり立てられた ３週間｡
あなたは 実に 嫌な男だったぜ｡
To be honest, I hated you.
I thought I would finally get back at you for what you put me through.
しごきの恨みを
今 晴らせると思ってたのによ｡
だが 師範代 あの世で見てなよ｡
But just watch me from up there, my instructor.
See the fruit of your torture!
あんたのしごきの 成果を！
おい こら エシディシ！
Hey, AC/DC. It's kinda early, but I'll be taking what's mine now.
てめえ あと６日あるが
今 もらうぜ｡
The antidote in your nose piercing is mine!
その鼻に おっつけた
ピアスの解毒剤をよ！
はぁ…➡
Stay out of my way. I don't have time to deal with you.
どけ！
今 お前を相手している 暇はない｡
暇？ お前にゃあ 俺以上に
いっぱい 暇はあるじゃあねえか！
Time? You've got a lot more time than I do!
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)ん…｡
ほう 鋭い…
いい目をするようになったな｡
Oh? That was sharp. I think you've grown smarter.
だが そのような まなざしを
持つ者が 俺に会ったとき➡
But when somebody looks at me like that...
そいつは 早死にする｡
...they're asking to die.
I'll tell you once more: Stay out of my way!
もう一度だけ 言う｡
どけい！ 俺に触れたら 貴様は
肉体を 半分以上 失うことになる｡
Touch me and half your body will be gone!
Make me!
どかしてみろ！
ぬう～ これは…｡
What's this?
Well? Get me out of your way!
どうした？ どかしてみろ｡
I only move if there's dog shit in my way!
俺が どくのは 道に
ウンコが落ちているときだけだぜ｡
ぬう…｡
His Ripple is breaking through my skin!
やつの波紋が 表皮のガードを破り
流れつつある｡➡
He's highly increased his control in just three weeks.
こいつ ３週の間に➡
これほどまでの波紋を
身に付けたか…➡
しかし！
ううっ!?
However!
ふ～む｡
うっ…｡
ちょいと 驚いたぞ
お前の成長には｡
I must say, your new skill surprises me.
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)だが 俺と戦う資格にゃあ
まだ 程遠かったな！➡
But you're still far from ready to go up against me!
I met and devoured countless Ripple users
like you just two-thousand years ago!
貴様程度の 波紋使いには➡
2,000年前 飽きるほど出会って
食らっているわ！
うがぁ～！
If I snap your finger off, you'll never use it again!
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)
このまま ねじり へし折れば➡
もう 指から
波紋を流せんだろう！
うおおおおおお！
Like this!
ほれぇ！
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)はっ！
やっと 気付いたかよ｡
You finally noticed?
今 てめえの腕にゃあ
細い絹糸が 巻きつきつつある！
Your arm is wrapped up in a fine silk thread.
糸には
波紋が伝わりやすいように➡
It's soaked in vegetable oil, which makes it
an excellent conductor of the Ripple!
植物油が
たっぷり 染み込ましてある｡
ホントは 首に
巻きつけてやるつもりだったが➡
I was aiming for your neck, but there was no chance!
さすがに その隙はねえな！
いつの間に 糸を張っていたのか!?
H-How did you do that?!
あっ… ぬぅ…➡
あ… あれは!?
That's...
This is morbid, even for me...
俺の作戦としては
ちょいと 残酷趣味だが➡
...but first blood goes to me and my instructor, AC/DC!
師範代と協力してあげた
ダメージ１ってとこか！
エシディシ！
GOHHHHHHHH！
2,500 years ago, a Chinese man wrote The Art of War.
2,500年前の 中国の兵法書に➡
｢孫子｣ってのがあって
こう書かれている｡
This is what he said:
"Victory is decided before the battle is fought."
勝利というのは 戦う前に
全て 既に決定されている｡
That means laying strategies while your opponent is unaware!
つまりだな… 戦う前に
敵に気付かれないよう➡
いろんな作戦を 練っとくのさ！
I'll admit I liked to play hooky from school...
俺は よく
学校は サボっていたがよ｡
エリナおばあちゃんから 教わって
歴史だけは 得意なのよ！
...But Granny Erina made sure I studied history!
お前は 長生きしとるけど➡
You may have lived a long time,
but you don't have a head for strategy!
策を考える頭が
俺より バカってことだな！
ギャハハハ！
このっ！
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)うぬぬぅ… き… 貴様！
W-Why you-!
おっ！ 怒るの？
Oh? Getting a bit mad?
波紋で 腕を蒸発させられて
怒り狂うの？
Are you upset that I disintegrated your arm?
Well get upset! I'm far more furious!
どんどん 怒りやがれ！
俺は もっと 頭にきてるんだ！
Because of that ring you put in me, I haven't slept right in weeks!
首に埋め込まれた
毒の指輪のおかげで この３週間！
夜も ぐっすり 眠れねえ！
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)う… うう…｡
ん？
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)う～！
あんまりだ～！
You're such a meanie!
HEEEEYYYY！
You're so mean to me!
あァァんまりだァァァァァ！
W-What's he doing?!
《何だ!? 一体…
な… 泣いている｡➡
H-He's bawling!
I thought he'd flip his lid for sure! This AC/DC is full of surprises!
血管ピクピクで
怒ってくると思いきや➡
この エシディシって野郎
予想外！➡
き… 気持ち悪いぜ…➡
T-This is embarrassing. He's throwing a tantrum!
だだっ子のように
泣きわめいてやがる》
AHYYY AHYYYY AHY！
WHOOOOHHHHH！
My poor arm!
俺の腕が～！
Some things are even scarier than anger...
《怒るより ぎゃ… 逆に
不気味なものがあるぜ｡➡
早いとこ とどめを刺そう！》
I'll finish this quickly!
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼの泣き声)
うっ!?
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)ふぅ…｡
Ah, that's much better.
ふぅ… すっとしたぜ｡
Sometimes my emotions get the best of me.
俺は ちと 荒っぽい性格でな｡
When I'm about to lose it, I calm down by crying for a bit.
激高しそうになると➡
泣きわめいて 頭を
冷静にすることにしているのだ｡
うっ… くっ…｡
You mentioned Sun Tzu, right?
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)｢孫子｣とかを
引き合いに出したな｡➡
I know of him as well.
それなら 俺も知っている｡➡
その昔
中国に行ったこともあるのでな｡
Long ago, I journeyed to China.
｢兵は詭道なり！｣
All war is deception. To fight is to delude.
戦いとは 欺くこと！
敵を怒らせて 心を動揺させれば
その力に 隙が生じる｡
Anger your enemies to lure them into mistakes.
That's your plan, right? I won't fall for that.
貴様が やろうとしているのは
それだろう｡
その手には 乗らん｡
ううっ!?
But Jojo, I really am shocked at your improvements.
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)しかし ジョジョとやら
貴様の成長には 驚がくした｡
I admire your Ripple.
貴様の波紋を 賛美しよう｡➡
I've been waiting for a worthy opponent.
久しく
好敵手がいなかったのでな｡
W-What are you doing to his arm?!
て… てめえ 遺体の腕を！
はぁ… ちょいと細めだが➡
It's a bit thin, but it will grow stronger in time.
そのうち 一体化して
元の太さになるだろう｡
《くっ！ な… 何だ？ こいつ！➡
H-He's too much!
He was bawling just a minute ago!
怒ったり 泣いたり
けろっとしたり！》
Oh, Jojo, I believe I've frightened you!
おっ ジョジョ！
ちょっと 恐れたな｡
Admit it, you're scared of me!
この俺に
今 恐怖を覚えただろう｡
うう!?
H-He's unreadable!
《よ… 読めん｡
俺は いつも 戦うときは➡
I've always read my opponents and used their feelings against them...
相手の気持ちとか
心の動きを読んで➡
それを 利用してきた｡➡
だが こいつは 予想外の
精神パターンを持っている｡➡
...but AC/DC's personality is beyond me.
読まれているのは
俺の方じゃあねえのか!?》
Am I the one being read here?!
なっ!?
ロ… ロギンズ師範代の遺体が！
W-What's happening to Loggins' body?!
うわっ！ あ… 熱い！
I-It's hot!
H-His body is boiling!
こ… これは
遺体が 煮立っている！
一体 何を!?
How the hell-?!
動物は 運動や病気で
エネルギーを使うと➡
An animal's temperature rises when it moves or is fighting disease.
体温が ある程度 上がる…｡
俺は 血液を 500度まで上昇させ
放出できる！
I can bring my blood up to 500 degrees and expel it.
腕を切断してやるとき➡
I sent my boiling blood coursing through him when I took off his arm.
傷口から 俺の血を送り込んで
沸騰させた｡➡
ワムウは 神砂嵐という
風を操る流法を 持つが➡
Wham can control the wind with his Holy Sandstorm and wind mode...
俺は 炎のエシディシ｡➡
...but I am The Blazing AC/DC.
熱を操る流法！
My mode is that of heat!
Your power to completely destroy a body is incredible!
人間の遺体を そこまで
徹底的に 破壊したのは➡
確かに すさまじいが➡
わざわざ そんな演出で➡
But I can tell you're just using it as a tactic to scare me!
この俺を 怖がらせようという
魂胆は 見え見えだぜ！
Try a Clacker Volley!
食らえ！ クラッカーヴォレイ！
My Ripple isn't like it was a month ago!
俺の波紋は １か月前とは違うぜ！
うっ…｡
ううっ！
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)やっぱり 恐怖してたな｡➡
I really did frighten you.
心の動揺で 焦りができ➡
Your emotions caused you to attack recklessly and too soon, Jojo.
安易な方法で 攻撃してきたのは
貴様の方だった ジョジョ｡
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)
頭に 血管針を突き刺して➡
My veins will inject boiling blood into your head and turn it into stew!
沸騰血を 体内に送り込み➡
お前の顔面を
ぐつぐつのシチューにしてやる｡
This is why it is called the Burning King Mode!
食らってくたばれ！
怪焔王の流法！
あっ… ぐああ～！
(ｸﾞﾗｽが割れる音)
ん？
Jojo...
《ジョジョ…》
Take this, Caesar!
食らえ シーザー！
Bubble Launcher!
シャボンランチャー！
うぉぉうっ！
はあっ！
待て！ ここまでだ｡
Stop! That's enough!
あっ！
If we continue, one or both of us will die.
(ﾒｯｼｰﾅ)これ以上 続けば いずれか
あるいは ２人とも死ぬ！➡
No, I hate to admit it, but I would lose.
いや いまいましいが
負けるのは 俺の方か｡
I have trained here ten years longer than you...
ここでの修行は
お前より 10年先輩だが➡
貴様の 波紋のスパークで➡
...but your Ripple burned off all the hair on my right arm.
右腕の産毛が
全部 抜けちまいやがった！
(ﾒｯｼｰﾅ)こんなに みっともなく
させられたんじゃしかたねえなぁ｡
What can I do after being shamed like this?
You passed your final exam with flying colors, Caesar!
(ﾒｯｼｰﾅ)最終試練
文句なく合格だ！ シーザー！
You're more interested in your good-for-nothing friend's exam, Caesar?
自分が 合格したことより➡
あの いいかげん野郎の最終試練が
そんなに 気になるか？ シーザー｡
I am only this strong because I didn't want Jojo to outdo me.
俺が ここまで
強い波紋を 身に付けられたのは➡
ジョジョの成長に
負けまいとしたからだ｡
そして 俺も ジョジョも➡
Both Jojo and I have to survive our upcoming battles.
あの ３人との戦いに
生き残るんだ｡
言っておくが ジョジョは➡
I'll say this, Jojo seems lazy and impudent...
いいかげんな 減らず口をたたくが
やつの良さは 心の底の方にある｡
...but he's good deep down.
けっ！ お前は
友人をつくるのは へたくそだが➡
You're bad at making friends, but when you do, I guess it's for life.
一度 ほれ込むと 女以上だぜ｡
あ… あれは!?
T-That's-!
AC/DC!
エシディシ！
ちっ！
味な方法で かわしやがった｡
That was a clever dodge.
や… やつの血管針を
マスクで防いだのはいいが…｡
T-The mask protected me, but...
ぐあああああっ！
む!?
うあああああ！
あ… あちちちぃ！
H-Hot hot hot hot!
なんて血液だ！
Damn this blood!
うっ！
Goddammit! These sexy lips finally come out from under the mask...
ちくしょう！
久しぶりに セクシーな唇を➡
マスクの外へ
出せたっつうのによォ｡
...and you just burned them, asshole!
ちょっぴり 焦げ目が
付いちまったぜ この野郎！
ジョジョ お前 今➡
Jojo, on the surface you make witty banter...
そんな 減らず口を
たたくふりをして➡
...but in your head, you're hatching a plan, aren't you?
実は 心の中で
作戦を考えているのだろ？
うぅっ！
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)おっ 青ざめたな ｼﾞｮｼﾞｮ｡➡
You've turned pale, Jojo!
Did I hit the mark? Did I hit the nail on the head?!
図星だろう？ ずばり
当たってしまったかなァーッ!?
うっ…｡
《フッ… 次の俺の作戦は…》
My next plan is...
I-I'll use the string!
《や… やはり 糸の作戦でいく➡
やつの攻撃から
身をかわすと 見せて➡
I'll act like I'm dodging...
逃げ回りながら この針の先端に
糸を結んで 四方に張っていく！➡
...but I'll run a string along these spikes while I move.
やつに 糸がバレないように｡➡
I can't let him catch on...
その糸の結界に
やつが 入ってきたら➡
Once he steps inside the string,
I'll wrap him up, then use the Ripple!
やつの体に 糸を巻きつけ
波紋で倒す！》
ハハハ…｡
うっ！
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)ハハハハ…｡
T-That laugh means trouble!
《く… くそ… 嫌な笑いだぜ｡➡
C-Could he be reading my plan?!
ま… まさか この作戦を
見抜いているのでは？➡
いや バレるものか！》
No, that's impossible!
はっ！
ハハハハ…｡
フフフ…｡
ふん！
ああっ！
Blazing King! Wheel of the Juggernaut Mode!
怪焔王 大車獄の流法！
うおっ！ ぬうっ！
How long do you think you can keep avoiding my attacks?
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)
この エシディシの流法から
いつまで 逃げ回れるかな？
ふん…｡
なっ!?
So you noticed at last.
やっと 気付いたようだな｡
どうして 俺の帽子が
ちっちゃくなっていくのかに！
Why is my hat shrinking?
You're caught in my web!
お前は 結界の中にいる！
My hat is 100% wool. It conducts the Ripple just great.
この帽子は ウール100％よ｡
波紋は よく伝導するぜ！
へえ～…｡
な… 何だ？ その笑いは｡
まだ 笑ってられるのか!?
W-Why are you smiling?
What are you hiding?
お前の 次のせりふは➡
Your next line is, "I'll wipe that smirk off your face!"
｢消してやるぜ
その にやついた顔を！｣だ｡
I'll wipe that smirk off your face!
消してやるぜ
その にやついた顔を！
はっ！
お… 俺の得意の おはこを!?
B-But that's my trick!
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)
結界だと!? よ～く見ろ！➡
A web? Look around you!
結界を張っていたのは 俺の方だ！
I am the one spinning a web!
I knew about your little plan all along!
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)貴様の作戦なんぞ
既に見切っているぜ！
くっ！
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)フフフフ…➡
ジョジョ
お前 さっき こう言っていたな？
Jojo, what was it you were saying before?
"Victory is decided before the battle is fought," was it?
｢勝利とは 戦う前に
既に決定されている｣とか｡➡
True, true.
まさに！ まさに！
まさにィィィィィィー！➡
True, true, true!
まさに 貴様の言うとおりよな！
How very true your words were!
うっ…｡
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)もっとも 上をいき➡
But my plans went far deeper than yours and decided my victory!
勝利を 決定していたのは
俺の策の方ではあったがな！
今から この 全ての血管針で
突き刺し開けた➡
My veins have given you some new holes.
Now I'll fill them all with my burning blood!
貴様の 全身の 穴という穴に
俺の熱血を 送り込み➡
You'll look like a lovely birthday cake covered in candles!
バースデーケーキの
ろうそくのように➡
きれいに 火をともして
焼いてくれるぜ！
絶体絶命！
He's on the edge of defeat!
や… やられる！
H-He won't make it!
Caesar!
(ﾒｯｼｰﾅ)シーザー！
はっ！
Judging from what I can see, I assume Loggins is dead.
(ﾒｯｼｰﾅ)状況から察するに➡
ロギンズのやつは
殺されてしまったようだ｡
If Jojo falls, AC/DC will come after us next.
もし ジョジョが倒されるのなら➡
今度 エシディシを
迎え撃つのは 我々だ！
はっ！
(ﾒｯｼｰﾅ)救いに行くには 遠いし➡
Jojo's too far away for us to help now...
もう 既に遅すぎる！
It hurts, but we have to think about Lisa Lisa and the Stone.
つらいことだが
我々が 考えねばならぬことは➡
リサリサと 赤石を守ること！
Now, let's prepare to move.
さあ 迎え撃つ準備をするぞ！
うっ… ジョジョ…｡
Jojo...
うっ…｡
Let me hear your screams as you twitch and writhe in despair, Jojo!
絶望のォ
ひきつり 濁った 叫び声を➡
聞かしてみせてくれ ジョジョ！
ふん…｡
フフフフ…｡
You laugh as I have you on the verge of death?
貴様は 今
生死を 俺につかまれている➡
こんなときに 笑みを！
恐怖のあまり 気でも違ったか!?
Has the fear driven you mad?
あのな こうやって
腕を組んで 目を閉じる笑いは➡
Well...
My arms are folded and my eyes are closed.
This is a victory laugh, AC/DC.
勝利の笑いだぜ｡
エシディシ
お前の敗因は やはり➡
You lost today because you snoozed for two-thousand years.
2,000年間 ぐっすりと
眠り込んでいたことだなぁ｡
I lost?! You're telling me I lost?!
敗因？ 敗因だと!?
Oh? You don't get it?
おや？ 分からない？
You can't read me?
お前は
俺の心の中が 分からない？
You don't understand that you already lost?
そして お前は 自分が
既に負けているのが 分からない？
You said your plans went deep, but mine went even deeper!
俺の上を いったつもりでも➡
そのさらに上を
俺が いってたのよ！
Humans have been making progress for the last two-thousand years.
人間はな 2,000年間 少しずつ
進歩してきたということだ｡
In the 18th and 19th centuries,
sleight-of-hand became a form of entertainment.
つまんないことだが
18世紀から 19世紀にかけて➡
手品や 奇術も 随分
ｴﾝﾀｰﾃｲﾝﾒﾝﾄとして 発展したんだ｡
And I happen to be a big fan.
俺 非常に好きなのよ｡
だましの手品が！
Illusion is my thing!
B-But I cut those strings!
せ… 切断したはずの…
ま… まさか 糸が！
I-Impossible! The strings are...
My rope magic worked!
ロープマジック成功！
俺は 糸を切断されても
大丈夫なように➡
I laid my trap so that even if the string were cut, it would be safe.
トリックを使って
結界を張っていた｡
Even if these points are severed,
the white portions can pull
the whole string together.
簡単な手品だ！
A simple trick.
RRRRRUUOOOOHHHHHHH！
Now you'll say, "My veins will move faster than your pathetic Ripple!"
貴様の 次のせりふは➡
｢貧弱な 波紋より先に➡
俺の血管針を
ぶち込んでくれる！｣だ！
My veins will move faster than your pathetic Ripple!
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)貧弱な 波紋より先に➡
俺の血管針を
ぶち込んでくれるわ！
コォー…｡
Feel the beat of my Ripple Overdrive!
食らえ！ 波紋疾走のビート！
(ｴｼﾃﾞｨｼ)RRRRRRRUUOOOOHHHHHHH！➡
俺が… 俺が…｡
I can't... I can't...
You're a human...
俺が 人間なんぞに…｡
I... I... I am the highest life form!
俺は… 俺は…
俺は 偉大な生き物だ！
や… やられるなんて よくも！
I won't be defeated!
That's it!
おのれ！ よくも こんな！
You've pushed me too far!
DDDOOOHHHHHH！
ギャアアアアアアー！
AC/DC's body is leaking some kind of energy!
な… 何かの エネルギーが➡
エシディシの体内から
放出されていく！
何千年も生き抜いた
こいつの生命力か｡
Is it the energy from a millennium of life?
Die already!
去りやがれ！
Die with the power you stole from thousands of innocents!
何万人もの人間を 殺して得た➡
そのパワーの
ほとばしりと共に！
My instructor, I have to thank you for torturing me.
師範代 あんたの しごきに対して
礼を言うぜ｡
Grazie, Loggins!
グラッチェ ロギンズ！
(ﾋﾟｱｽの落ちる音)
ふぅ…｡
Santana turned to stone and only feigned death.
サンタナを やっつけたときは➡
岩になって
仮死状態で生きていた｡
But even AC/DC's bones were destroyed.  What makes him different?
エシディシは
骨まで 消滅しやがったが➡
どうも その違いが 気になるな｡
Maybe it's just because my Ripple became stronger.
でも まあ… 俺の波紋の
成長の証拠と思ってみっか｡
やつは死んで 喉のリングの
解毒剤も 手に入れたしな｡
He's dead now, and I have one of the antidotes I need.
うう…｡
ああ…｡
I guess it reminds me of snot because it's dripping from a nose piercing.
鼻に着けてた ピアスのせいか➡
何か この ドロリっての
鼻水のイメージがあるけど…｡
Anyway, I have to drink it...
まあ… 飲んでみるか｡
うっ… ああっ…｡
よし！ 解毒剤は効いたぜ｡
All right! I think it worked.
何となく 首のリングが➡
The ring around my windpipe is gone.
なくなった感じが
実感としてある｡
どれ シーザーや
リサリサの所へ 戻るか｡
So, now I'll go see Caesar and Lisa Lisa.
I think I used my head too much against AC/DC. My shoulders are sore!
エシディシ戦は
体力より 頭を使ったせいか➡
どうも 肩が凝ったなあ｡
(鼻歌)
Time Until The Remaining Ring Dissolves:
6 Days
♬(ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞﾃｰﾏ)
I'll be the roundabout
♬ I'll be the roundabout
The words will make you out 'n' out
♬ The words
will make you out'n'out
♬ I spend the day away
I'll spend the day your way
♬ Call it morning
driving through
Call it morning driving through the sound and
♬ the sound and
in and out the valley
In and out the valley
♬～
The music dance and sing
♬ The music dance and sing
♬ They make
the children really ring
They make the children really ring
I'll spend the day your way
♬ Spend the day away
Call it morning driving through the sound and
♬ Call it morning
driving through
♬ the sound and
in and out the valley
In and out the valley
In and around the lake
♬ In and around the lake
Mountains come out of the sky
♬ Mountains come out of
the sky and they stand there
and they stand there
One mile over we'll be there and we'll see you
♬ One mile over we'll be there
and we'll see you
♬ Ten true summers
Ten true summers we'll be there and laughing too
♬ we'll be there
and laughing too
Twenty-four before my love you'll see I'll be
♬ Twenty four before
my love you'll see
♬ I'll be there with you
There with you
Next Episode
How about the white one?
Wait until we cross!
But I really do like this design!
I'll eradicate them.
Which to choose?
Damn it! I can't hit her!
Episode 18:
"Stroheim's Revenge!"